

# MD ARIFUL ISLAM

BSC IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY & MANAGEMENT



+8801757210124



tasdeealarif@gmail.com



## Objective -

Dedicated to a career in data analysis and business analysis in the fields of business, engineering, science, and technology. Willing to face the obstacles and assume the duties of a dedicated data analyst. obtained a number of professional qualifications, including those in SQL, power bl, and Google analytics. able to use programming languages to confidently tackle statistical and mathematical challenges. Extremely motivated to research new technologies, learn them, and use them in the fields of business, science, and technology.



## **Education**

#### **BSc in Information Technology &** Management

January 2020- December 2023 (Ongoing) 3.81/4 CGPA (Average of 6 Semester) **Daffodil International University** 

**BSc in Computer Science** March 2022- August 2022 **University Kebangsaan Malaysia** (QS world Ranking 129th in 2023 year) Scholarship opportunity for one semester

## Relevant Academic Course

TTTC2453 – Machine Learning TC3283 – Data Mining (University Kebangsaan Malaysia)

ITM 221 – Database Management System ITM 302 - Business & Web Analytics ITM 318 – Data Structure & Algorithm (Daffodil International University)

### - Research Interest -

- Deep Learning
- Data Mining
- Semantic analysis

# Skills ———

**Programming** 

Language

• Python: Intermediate • SQL: Intermediate

• C: Intermediate • HTML. CSS3: Basic • Java: Basic • R: Basic

**Machine Learning** 

Supervised, Unsupervised, reinforcement

learning, Data analysis

**Python Libraries Deep Learning** Data Visualization Numpy, Pandas, Tensorflow, Keras.

CNNs, LSTM, RNNs, MLPs, DBNs Excel (intermediate), Power BI,

Orange, Google Data studio, BigML.

Intermediate

**Probability & Statistics** 

# **X**Achievement —



Got Scholarship opportunity based on merit & Finished One semester from University Kebangsaan Malaysia. (QS world Rank 2023- 129th)



Best Presenter & Best in Presentation among Philippines, at 2nd WORLDEX, Hosted By LPU Batangas Philippine.



1st Runner up at 3rd Data Summit Idea Contest, Hosted by Daffodil International University.



1st Runner up at HULT PRIZE at DIU 2023

# Experience –



Business Analyst at IDL-BD, (February 2023- Ongoing)



**Student Associate at Daffodil International University** (December 2022 - Ongoing)



Project Lead at ITM SUMMIT 2023. January 2023- March 4th 2023



Event Management Head at HULT PRIZE at DIU 2023 November 2022- February 26th 2023



College Prefect at Bangladesh Navy College, Khulna November 2016- March 31st 2018

### Soft Skills and Strengths ———

(Team Working) (Self Confidence) (Ability to Plan and Organize)

Creativity Problem Solving Love Learning New Things Leadership

#### - Personal Interest —

**Data Science** 

**Data Analysis** 

**Information Technology** 

Research

Software Testing

**Human Resource** 













• Orange : Heart disease reports analysis.

• Excel: Mobile sell Information in BD.

• Excel : Gaming Copies sold 1980-2020

• Google Data Studio: Blood Group Report analysis.

# Training Certification —

- Machine Learning course certificate from Stanford University
- Data Structure course certificate from Stanford University.
- Python for Data Science, AI & Development course certificate from IBM Skill Network.
- Data Analysis course certificate from Freecodecamp.com (300 Hours)



#### 1. Dr. Imran Mahmud

Associate Professor & Head Software Engineering Department **Daffodil International University** 

Email: imranmahmud@daffodilvarsity.edu.bd

**Cell phone:** +880 1711370502

#### 2. Nusrat Jahan

Assistant Professor and Head Information Technology & Management Department

**Daffodil International University** 

Email: nusrat.swe@diu.edu.bd Cell phone: +88 01847334996